# EVAN MISSHULA

http://Misshula.org

https://github.com/EvanMisshula

EvanMisshula@gmail.com, (917) 975-7039

### SUMMARY

Data Scientist with 8+ years of experience applying advanced mathematics to complex problems for business, government and non-profits. Frequent speaker to and active member of the NYC free software, functional programming, web development, data visualization and data science communities. Mathematical subject matter expertise includes Stochastic Differential Equations, Machine Learning, Bayesian Statistics, Functional Programming, Social Network Analysis, Simulation, Factor Analysis, Clustering, Random Forests and Support Vector Machines. Expert level programmer in R and Python. Major projects completed in C++, Java and Javascript. Competencies include Haskell and Clojure.

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD Criminal Justice (ABD) City University of New York, New York, NY

Yale University, New Haven, CT

February 2017 (expected) GPA 3.43 (CS) 3.85

BS Applied Math (Operations Research) and BA Economics & Mathematics

May 1988

CAREER HISTORY

Data Scientist, Misdemeanor Justice Project (MJP)

October 2016 - Present

The MJP seeks to understand the criminal justice response to low-level offenses, from arrest to disposition.

- Responsible for designing statistical tests and visualizations for a wide variety of non-felony police actions including misdemeanor arrests, summons and citations
- Created demographic profiles for Jurisdiction selection
- Prepared materials for and participated with MJP advisory board

Project Manager, Tech Talent Pipeline @ Queens College

October 2015 - October 2016

- Managed recruitment and placement for 50 CS interns at NYC tech startups (\$1 million budget)
- Increased applications 147% semester-on-semester
- Exceeded performance goals, including student placement and business recruitment

Substitute Lecturer, CUNY John Jay Math and Computer Science

July 2012 - Present

- Taught advanced data structures, (2 sections, 45 students) in C++ using version control and unit testing.
- Teaching Graduate Network Security from a book on which I will be a co-author.
- Advisor to the John Jay Computer Science club. Membership grew from 7 to more than 50 in one semester.

## SKILLS

Scheme, Bro

Compiled Languages: Go, C, C++, Java

Libraries: nodeJS, expressJS, ReactJS, D3JS, LeafletJS, ggplot2, Django, Flask, Hadoop, Spark, Scapy

Databases: MySql (proficient), Postgres (proficient), Postgis (proficient), Sqlite3

Operating Systems: Linux (proficient), Windows, Mac OS X, UNIX, Bash, Powershell

#### Fellowships, Awards and Honors

First place team, HeatseekNYC's Hack for Heat	$December\ 2015$
First place team, AT&T Wireless Hackathon for Good	$September\ 2015$
CUNY GC Digital Fellow, CUNY Graduate Center	2014 -2016
Provost's Digital Initiative grant winner, CUNY Graduate Center	2013 -2014
Fellow, University of Chicago, Data Science for Social Good	Summer 2013